Contact: <u>fareomg@gmail.com</u> / <u>Telegram</u> / <u>LinkedIn</u> / <u>GitHub</u>

Vladyslav Silich

Software Engineer

I'm a software engineer based in Kyiv with more than 5 years of experience in the software industry. My focus area for the past few years has been back end development with Node.js, but I'm also skilled in modern front end technologies and frameworks.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Ruby (Rails), SQL, bash

Front End Technologies: React, React Native, Ember.js, Next.js

Back End Technologies: Node.js, Nest.js, Fastify, Express

Other: Docker, k8s (basic usage), CI/CD (GitHub Actions, CircleCI, Gitlab CI), SQL/NoSQL databases (PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB), async messaging (RabbitMQ, Kafka, SQS), cloud services (AWS), testing (Mocha, Jest, Cypress and others), Redis, gRPC, GraphQL, Websockets, payments systems (Stripe, Circle), solid understanding of good UX/UI and product design

EXPERIENCE

MWDN Ltd. Aug 2021 - present

Back End Developer (08/2021 - present)

- Technologies used: Node.js, gRPC, Go, CircleCI, AWS services, k8s, Docker
- Participated in developing payment system with cloud infrastructures

Kimby.io April 2022 - Aug 2022

Back End Developer (04/2022 - 08/2022)

- Technologies used: Node.js, gRPC, GraphQL, Apollo, GitHub Actions, AWS services, k8s, Docker
- Responsible for design and development of the system of buying fractional ownership in collectible pieces

Testomat.io Apr 2021 - Mar 2022

Full Stack Developer (04/2021 - 03/2022)

- Technologies used: Ember.js, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, Docker
- Designed and built customer-facing UI for test management system
- Responsible for development of Node.js based tools and services

AWWCOR, Inc. Apr 2019 - July 2021

Back End Developer (04/2019 - 08/2021)

- Technologies used: Node.js, MySQL, Redis, AWS services, Docker
- Responsible for design and development of innovative clinical business technology solutions and software services

Contact: <u>fareomg@gmail.com</u> / <u>Telegram</u> / <u>LinkedIn</u> / <u>GitHub</u>

NordWhale Sep 2020 - Nov 2020

Full Stack Developer (09/2020 - 11/2020)

- Technologies used: React, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, AWS services
- Participated in product software engineering as a full stack developer

Binary Studio Academy

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

JavaScript Developer, Intern (06/2019 - 09/2019)

- Technologies used: React/Redux, React Native, PostgreSQL, Websockets, Node.js
- Worked on <u>Fantasy Football League</u> with a <u>mobile app</u>: online game where participants select a team of real players and all the results of the players totally depend on the statistics of those players in real games

iDevelop City Inc.

Dec 2017 - Sep 2018

Python Developer, Intern (06/2018 - 09/2018)

- Technologies used: Python 3, numpy, Docker
- Developed backend components for correct modeling of the building structures
- Identified and rectified programming flaws in co-operation with the zoning team

Data Entry Specialist (12/2017 - 06/2018)

- Provided a visually easy way to view the interpretation of the zoning restrictions
- Made database changes and upgraded the information by inputting new data

CERTIFICATIONS

- JSNAD: OpenJS Node.js Application Developer by OpenJS Foundation
- JSNSD: OpenJS Node.js Services Developer by OpenJS Foundation
- M220JS: MongoDB for Javascript Developers by MongoDB University
- English Proficiency Certificate by Duolingo

EDUCATION

Vilnius Gediminas Technical University

Sep 2022 - present

Information Systems Software Engineering, Master's degree

Faculty of Fundamental Sciences

NTUU "Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

Sep 2021 - Aug 2022

Software Engineering, Master's degree

Faculty of Heat Power Engineering

NTUU "Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

Sep 2016 - Jun 2020

Cybersecurity, Bachelor's degree

Institute of Physics and Technology